C. Glenn Carrington papers, 1923-1965
Emory University
C. Glenn Carrington papers, 1923-1965
Carrington, C. Glenn, 1904-1975.
Manuscript Collection No. 1026
.75 linear ft. (2 boxes)
Papers of C. Glenn Carrington, African American collector closely associated with prominent figures of the Harlem Renaissance, including correspondence and manuscripts and printed material signed by Langston Hughes.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purchase, 2005.
Restrictions on access
Unrestricted access.
Biographical Note
Calvin Glenn Carrington (1904-1975) was an African American collector closely associated with prominent figures of the Harlem Renaissance. He was born in Richmond, Virginia, on May 7, 1904 to Fannie and David Carrington. He received a BA from Howard University and an MA in social work from Columbia University. In addition to becoming one of the first African American parole officers in New York State, he also served as a social worker. C. Glenn Carrington died June 12, 1975.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains material collected by C. Glenn Carrington. The majority of the papers consists of signed and inscribed manuscripts by Langston Hughes, including poetry, play scripts, and drafts of book-length manuscripts, and a few printed programs and pamphlets featuring Hughes. Of particular interest is a typescript copy of Hughes' remarks at the National Poetry Festival in 1962 and corrected draft copies of "Tambourines to Glory." The majority of the manuscripts are signed and dated. The Carrington papers also include a small amount of personal correspondence addressed to Carrington from Countee Cullen, Harold Jackman, and Arthur A. Schomburg.
Related Materials in Other Repositories
C. Glenn Carrington papers, Moorland-Springarn Research Center, Howard University and Glenn Carrington papers, Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, New York Public Library.
Arrangement Note
Arranged by document type.
Selected Search Terms
Personal Names
Cullen, Countee, 1906-1946.; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967.; Jackman, Harold, 1901-1961.; Schomburg, Arthur Alfonso, 1874-1938.
Topical Terms
African American dramatists.; African American poets.; American poetry--African American authors--20th century.; Harlem Renaissance.
Form/Genre Terms
Manuscripts.; Poems.; Scripts.
Occupation
Collector.
Container List
- Personal papers
- Correspondence, 1923-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Collected Langston Hughes manuscripts
- Anthology of American Negro Poetry (translation into French by Langston Hughes) [signed typescript] (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Biographical material [signed typescripts], 1958, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Book title lists [signed typescripts] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Commentary on "When Sue Wears Red," "The Negro Speaks of Rivers," "Song for a Banjo Dance," "The Weary Blues," and "Early Evening Quarrel" for Thomas Edward Francis, [signed typescript], 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Educational pamphlet, "Langston Hughes - Poet of the People" [inscribed to Glenn] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Famous Negro Heroes, Benjamin O. Davis Jr. entry [corrected and signed typescript], 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Famous Negro Heroes, correspondence concerning photograph permissions, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Famous Negro Heroes of America, I. Preliminary Notes [corrected and signed typescripts], 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Famous Negro Heroes of America, II. Original First Drafts [corrected and signed typescripts], 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Famous Negro Heroes of America, III. Final copy carbon [corrected and signed typescript], 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Liner notes, "Come on in the Room," by Clara Ward and Singers [signed typescript], 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lyrics, "Let Us Remember" [inscribed typescript to Glenn Carrington], 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lyrics, "Someone to Come Home to" from Simply Heavenly [inscribed typescript to Glenn Carrington] (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Play script, "Black Nativity," third draft [signed typescript], 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Play script, "The Prodigal Son" [signed typescript], 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Play script, "Simple Takes a Wife" [signed typescript], 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Play script, "Tambourines to Glory," original version [corrected and signed typescript], 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Play script, "Tambourines to Glory," rehearsal version [corrected and signed typescript], 1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Poetry, "A Ballad of Negro History (So Much to Write About)" [inscribed typescript to Glenn], 1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Poetry, "Border Line" (commentary for Dial Press), [signed typescript], 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Poetry, "Consider Me" [inscribed typescript to Glenn], 1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Poetry, "Death in Yorkville" [signed typescript], 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Poetry, "Encounter" [signed typescript], 1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Poetry, "Freedom Wind" [signed typescript], 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Poetry, "Layette" [typescript] (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Poetry, "Little Dreams" [signed typescript], 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Poetry, "Low to High" [inscribed typescript to Glenn], 1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Poetry, "Mighty Marching Morning" [typescript] (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Poetry, "On a Christmas Night" [signed typescript] (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Poetry, "Poem for a Man" [signed typescript], 1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Poetry, Russian poems translated by Langston Hughes [signed typescript], 1933 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Poetry, "Small Memory" [signed typescript], 1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Poetry, "Tambourines" [typescript] (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Poetry, "The Train That Took Wings and Flew" [signed typescript], 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Poetry, "Wait a Minute River" [inscribed typescript to Glenn], 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Program, "An Evening with Langston Hughes," 39th Annual Negro History Week Celebration, February 9, 1964 [inscribed typescript to Glenn Carrington] (Box 2, Folder 16)
- National Poetry Festival, Langston Hughes reading and program [inscribed typescript to Glenn Carrington], 1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)